Robert Orben Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Robert Orben Papers 1941-2019
MSS86325
Orben, Robert
23,800 items
52 containers plus 17 oversize
35.8 linear feet
81 digital files (5.88GB)
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Comedy writer and political speechwriter. Correspondence, jokes and other writings, business papers, photographs, printed matter, interviews, and speeches in both physical and digital formats pertaining to Orben's work as a comedy writer and humor consultant for entertainers, public figures, and corporate clients, editor of a topical humor service, writer for television, and speechwriter for President Gerald R. Ford.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Kupferman, Stanley.; Orben, Robert.
Organizations
Orben Publications.
Subjects
American periodicals.; American wit and humor.; Amusements--Periodicals.; Booksellers and bookselling.; Comedians.; Comedy sketches.; Comedy--Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Comedy--Periodicals.; Comedy.; Current events--Humor.; Entertainers.; Magic tricks.; Magicians.; Politics and culture--Humor.; Public speaking.; Publishers and publishing.; Speechwriting.; Television comedies.; Television programs--United States.; Wit and humor--Authorship.; Wit and humor--Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Wit and humor.
Places
United States--Humor.
Titles
Orben's current comedy (periodical); Red Skelton hour (Television program)
Occupations
Comedy writers.; Speechwriters.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Robert Orben were given to the Library of Congress by Orben in 2019.
Transfers
Some audio and video tapes have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division where they are identified as part of the Robert Orben Papers. Patrons are encouraged to contact the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division in advance of a research visit.
Other Repositories
Other papers of Robert Orben can be found in the Gerald R. Ford Library, Ann Arbor, Mich.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Robert Orben are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Technical Requirements
Digital files are audio files (.wav), PowerPoint 97 and 2016 presentation files (.ppt), and video files (.vob).
Biographical Note
Date Event
1927, March 4 Born, New York, N.Y.
1945 Married Jean Louise Connelly Served in United States Army, Fort Dix, N.J., and Camp Joseph T. Robinson, Little Rock, Ark.
1946 1964 Wrote and published a series of books of humor material for performers
1946 1947 Wrote articles for Magic is Fun magazine
1948 1954 Columnist, Genii magazine
circa 1951 Writer, Fun with Felix television program
1958 1968 Founder and owner, Orben Publications with Stanley Kupferman
1958 1968 Published Orben's Current Comedy, a topical humor periodical
1961 circa 1967 Wrote material for comedian Dick Gregory
1962 Editor, From the Back of the Bus by Dick Gregory. N.Y.: Dutton
1962 1964 Writer, The Jack Paar Program
1964 1970 Writer, The Red Skelton Hour
1966 Published The Joke-Teller's Handbook, or 1,999 Belly Laughs. N.Y.: Doubleday
1969 Published The Ad-Libber's Handbook: 2000 New Laughs for Speakers. N.Y.: Doubleday
1960s 1990s Consultant, speechwriter for politicians and other public figures
1971 Resumed publishing Orben's Current Comedy Published The Encyclopedia of One-Liner Comedy. N.Y.: Doubleday
1971 1973 Founder and owner, The Comedy Center, a company that sold comedy products
1971 1972 Published Orben Comedy Letter
1971 1980 Published Orben's Comedy Fillers
1974 Consultant to Vice President Gerald R. Ford
1974 1975 Speechwriter and associate editor for President Gerald R. Ford
1976 1977 Director, White House Speechwriting Staff Special assistant to the President
1979 Published 2500 Jokes to Start 'Em Laughing. N.Y.: Doubleday
1970s 1990s Consultant, speechwriter, and advisor on the use of humor in public speaking for executives and corporations
1983 Published 2100 Laughs for All Occasions. N.Y.: Doubleday
1984 Published 2400 Jokes to Brighten Your Speeches. N.Y.: Doubleday
1986 Published 2000 Sure-Fire Jokes for Speakers: The Encyclopedia of One-Liner Comedy. N.Y.: Doubleday
2000 Published Speaker's Handbook of Humor. Springfield, Mass.: Merriam-Webster
2007 Published The Speechwriter's Handbook of Humor: A Practical Guide to Getting Laughs in Public Speeches and Presentations. Portland, Oreg.: Marion Street Press
2023, Feb. 2 Died, Alexandria, Va.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Robert Orben (1927-2023) span the dates 1941-2019. The collection documents Orben's career as a comedy writer and humor consultant, and speechwriter for President Gerald R. Ford. The papers are arranged into five series: General Correspondence, Alphabetical File, Speeches and Writings, Miscellany, and Oversize.
This collection documents Orben's work as a comedy writer and promoter of humor. Orben initially focused on magic and magicians, but over time expanded his reach and wrote material for use by a wide range of performers and public speakers. A strength of this collection is the compilation of jokes and one-liners he wrote over the second half of the twentieth century, that he published under his own name, prepared for other performers, created for The Red Skelton Hour television program, and supplied for corporate events. His periodical, Orben's Current Comedy, a topical subscription service, contains jokes relating to the public figures, cultural trends, and current events from 1958 to 1989. A smaller amount of similar material from the 1990s that he sent to columnists and others is dispersed throughout collection. Orben's work as a promoter of and advisor on the use of humor in public speaking and his life-long connection to magicians and the magic profession are also documented. The collection complements a larger collection of Robert Orben Papers at the Gerald R. Ford Library in Ann Arbor, Michigan. Material pertaining to Orben's time as a speechwriter in the Ford White House includes memorabilia, photographs, an oral history transcript, speeches, and an unpublished memoir.
The collection's series are listed and briefly described below. A fuller description of each series and a list of its contents can be accessed in the series descriptions within the container list.
The General Correspondence series comprises a chronological grouping of letters sent and received by Orben between the years 1963 and 2019.
The Alphabetical File series touches on all aspects of his career and documents Orben’s dealings with colleagues, publishers, publications, organizations, columnists, clients, and friends.
The Speeches and Writings series contains approximately sixty years of jokes, one-liners, writings, and remarks from Orben's career as a comedy writer and humor consultant for performers, television programs, public figures, and corporate clients.
A small Miscellany series contains additional material documenting Orben's life and career including press clippings and photographs depicting his work with President Gerald R. Ford.
The remaining series contains Oversize material.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in five series:
General Correspondence, 1963-2019
Alphabetical File, 1941-2019
Speeches and Writings, 1945-2018
Miscellany, 1945-2019
Oversize, 1945-1977
Container List
- General Correspondence, 1963-2019 (Box 1-2)
  The General Correspondence series comprises a chronological grouping of letters sent and received by Orben between the years 1963 and 2019. The letters date from the period that Orben moved to California to work as a writer for the television program, The Red Skelton Hour, and continue into his retirement years. While some of the correspondence relates to his work, much of it is of a personal nature. Additional correspondence, grouped alphabetically by name of correspondent or topic, is located in the Alphabetical File series.
  Material types include letters sent and received with related attachments. One attachment is in digital format as a PowerPoint presentation.
  Arranged chronologically. The file structure of the digital content maintained as received.
  - 1963-1979, (15 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1980-2019, (10 folders); Attachments to correspondence included storage media described below. (Box 2)
  - 2019, Nilsen, Alleen Pace, and Don L. F. Nilsen, The Language of Humor, PowerPoint presentation, mss86325_201_001
  - Undated (Box 2)
- Alphabetical File, 1941-2019 (Box 3-32)
  The Alphabetical File series touches on all aspects of his career and documents Orben’s dealings with colleagues, publishers, publications, organizations, columnists, clients, and friends. Files relating to Orben’s business partner in the 1960s, Stanley Kupferman, contain their extensive correspondence from when Orben was in California containing details about their business, Orben Publications, and their efforts to promote and sell Orben’s books and other comedy products. Orben’s letters to Kupferman also describe his experience as a writer for The Red Skelton Hour and touch on his work for comedian Dick Gregory. A large portion of this material dates from the years after Orben’s work for President Gerald R. Ford. Items relating to Gerald R. Ford include letters from Ford documenting Orben’s continued assistance with speeches in the years following his presidency and memorabilia from Orben’s time in the Ford White House.
  Material types include correspondence, business papers, printed matter, and one-liners and other humorous material Orben sent to individuals and publications.
  Arranged alphabetically by name or topic. The file structure of the digital content maintained as received.
  - 50 Plus magazine, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Acocella, Paul, 1993-2006, 2014 (Box 3)
  - Across the Board magazine, 1983-1984, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Adams, Joey, 1972-1976 (Box 3)
  - Adams, Patch, 1987-1988, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Adler & Robin Books, 1978, 1989-1992 (Box 3)
  - American Comedy Arts, circa 1974 (Box 3)
  - American Legion magazine, 1983 (Box 3)
  - American Management Associations, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - American Speaker magazine, circa 2000-2004 (Box 3)
  - American Way magazine, 1982-1988 (Box 3)
  - Associated Marketing Enterprises, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Back in the Bronx magazine, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Badler, Mitchell M., 1967-1970, 1981-1983, 1989-1992 (Box 3)
  - Bain, Donald, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Bakshian, Aram, Jr., 1992 (Box 3)
  - Bauer, Joseph C., 1974-1983 (Box 3)
  - Bause, Dave, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Bawl Street Journal, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Bedrosian, Maggie, 1996-2001 (Box 3)
  - Bergeron, Bev, 1996-2000, 2018 (Box 3)
  - Bergstrom, Karl, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Blaney, Walter, 1991-1999, 2010 (Box 3)
  - Blumenfeld, Esther, 1996-2012 (Box 4)
  - Blumenfeld, Esther, and Lynn Alpern, 1980-1990 (Box 4)
  - Book ideas, 1963-1971 (Box 4)
  - Books, miscellaneous information, 1960s-2000, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Booth, John, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Borealis Press, 2006-2012 (Box 4)
  - Boren, James H., 1972, 1986-2010, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Bosc, Joyce, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Branch, Charles, 1997-2002 (Box 4)
  - Brecher, Harold, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Brechtel, Warren R., 1989 (Box 4)
  - Breeskin, Barnee, 1981, 1989-1991, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Brooks, Foster, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Buchwald, Art, 1966, 2007 (Box 4)
  - Budler, Bob, 1990-1992 (Box 5)
  - Butler, Michael, 1981-1984 (Box 5)
  - Butler, Patrick, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Buttons, Red, 1964, 1970-1972, 1982-2006, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Campaign Associates, 1973-1975 (Box 5)
  - Campaign magazine, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Campaigns & Elections magazine, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Capitol Comedy newsletter, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Carlston, Greg, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Carpenter, Liz, circa 1980-1983, 1994-2010 (Box 5)
  - Carter, Diane, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Carver, Ron, undated (Box 5)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Chapel, Gage William, 1975-1978, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Cimberg, Alan, 1995-2000 (Box 5)
  - Columnists, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Comedy & Entertainment magazine, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Comedy Center, 1971-1991 (Box 5)
  - Comedy Center, 1971-1991, (6 folders) (Box 6)
  - Communicator's Journal, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Computer retrieval, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Contributors article, 1977, undated (Box 6)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Copyright information, 1963-1991, 1993-1991 (Box 7)
  - Copyrights, 1946-1988, (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - Copyrights, 1946-1988, (4 folders) (Box 8)
  - Costello, John, 1977, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Creative Concepts, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Crofts, Peter, 1984-1988 (Box 8)
  - Cummings, Herb, and Barbara Cummings, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Current Comedy, 1964-1991 (Box 8)
  - Current Comedy, 1964-1991, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Daly, John Jay, 1978-1979, 1991-1992, 1998-2009 (Box 9)
  - Dawson, Donald S., 1995 (Box 9)
  - Dechau, Gary, 1992-2000 (Box 9)
  - Dechter & Kornbluth, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Delaney, Mick, 1973-1986, 1994-1996 (Box 9)
  - Dickson, Paul, 1992-1996 (Box 9)
  - Dolphin Enterprises agreement, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Doubleday & Co. (Box 9)
    - 2100 Laughs for All Occasions, 1982-1990 (Box 9)
    - 2400 Jokes to Brighten Your Speeches, 1980-1989 (Box 10)
    - 2500 Jokes to Start 'Em Laughing, 1978-1988 (Box 10)
    - Ad-Libber's Handbook, 1969-1971, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Book and author talks, 1971-1973 (Box 10)
    - Encyclopedia of One-Liner Comedy, 1971-1985, 1995 (Box 10)
    - Humor division, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Joke-Teller's Handbook, 1964-1968, 1975-1979 (Box 10)
    - Miscellany, 1970, 1983-1993, 1999 (Box 10)
    - Promotion, 1966-1968, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Dunn, Jerry Camarillo, Jr., 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Dunn, Joseph R., 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - Dunn, Ricki, 2006 (Box 11)
  - Dynamic Years magazine, 1979-1984 (Box 11)
  - Eberhart, Elvin (Cy), 1993-2012 (Box 11)
  - Elnicky, Robert N., 1989-2002 (Box 11)
  - Elnicky, Robert N., video files, 2002, undated, mss86325_201_007; mss86325_201_008
  - Emery, Harold, 1966-1969 (Box 11)
  - Erickson, Lou, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Ewald, William Bragg, Jr., and Mary Ewald, 1994-2001 (Box 11)
  - Executive Fitness newsletter, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Executive Speaker newsletter, 1985-1992 (Box 11)
  - Family Circle magazine 1978 (Box 11)
  - Family Weekly, 1971-1979 (Box 11)
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1978-1981, 1990-1994 (Box 11)
  - Fassihi, Theresa, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Fechtner, Leopold, 1976, 1983, 1999-2001 (Box 12)
  - Feinberg, Leonard, and Lilian Feinberg, 1978-1982, 1990-2006 (Box 12)
  - Financial Executives Institute, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Fitzgerald, Peter, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Florentine, Zina, 1973-1980 (Box 12)
  - Ford, Gerald R. (Box 12)
    - Christmas cards, 1976-2006 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1968-2018 (Box 12)
    - Miscellany, 1979-2011, (4 folders) (Box 12)
    - Miscellany, 2012-2015 (Box 13)
    - White House memorabilia, 1975-1977 See also Oversize, (4 folders) (Box 13)
  - Frank Wright Associates, 1972-1979 (Box 13)
  - Franklin, Ben B., 1980-2000 (Box 13)
  - Fry, William F., 1997-1999 (Box 14)
  - Gardner, Gerald, 1985-1992 (Box 14)
  - Gardner, Martin, 1991-2010, (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - Gary, Harold, 1974 (Box 14)
  - Geller, Judith, 2006 (Box 14)
  - George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1991-1992 (Box 14)
  - Gerald R. Ford Foundation, 2004-2019, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Gerald. R. Ford Library, Ann Arbor, Mich. (Box 15)
    - Dedication, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Robert Orben Papers, 1990, 2005-2006, 2015 (Box 15)
  - Gingras, Angèle de T., 1987-1996 (Box 15)
  - Gliner, Art, 1947-1963, 1991-2011 (Box 15)
  - Glucksman, Ernest D., 1978 (Box 15)
  - Gold, Bill, 1993-2000 (Box 15)
  - Gold, Victor, 1990, 2007 (Box 15)
  - Golomb, Frederick M., 1986 (Box 15)
  - Good Morning America, television program, 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - Gordon, Bill, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Gore, James, 1968-1972, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Gove, Bill, 1977-2002 (Box 15)
  - Green, Abel, 1964-1973, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Greene, Mort, 1970-1992 (Box 15)
  - Gregory, Dick (Box 16)
    - Air spots, 1965 (Box 16)
    - Back of the Bus, 1961-1969 (Box 16)
    - Miscellany, 1965-1970 (Box 16)
    - What's Happening, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Grossman, John, 1978-1995 (Box 16)
  - Haband Company, 1968-1973, (4 folders) (Box 16)
  - Hall, Floyd, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Halligan, Robert A., 1988-2007, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - Harry Byrd Kline Celebrity Service, 1972-1974 (Box 17)
  - Hartmann, Robert Trowbridge, 1978, 1992, 2008 (Box 17)
  - Harvey, Paul, 1983, 1991-2001, 2008-2009 (Box 17)
  - Hawkins, Robert, 1994-1999 (Box 17)
  - Heinz, John F., 1983-2004, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Helitzer, Mel, 1984-1986, 1998-2003, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Helitzer, Mel, audio files, 2002, mss86325_201_002
  - Henrichs, Garth, 1978-1981, 1990-2002, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Hercer, Edmund R., 1981-1984, 1998-2003, 2012 (Box 17)
  - Hersey, Ross V., 1995-1999 (Box 17)
  - Hill, I. William, and Lou-Lou Hill, 1982-1983, 1989-1998 (Box 17)
  - Hoffmeister, Bruce F., 1991 (Box 18)
  - Hollywood School of Comedy Writing, Hollywood, Calif., 1967-1971 (Box 18)
  - Holst, Art, 1996 (Box 18)
  - House of Humour and Satire, Gabrovo, Bulgaria, 1984 (Box 18)
  - "How-to" topics, 1971-1987, (6 folders) (Box 18)
  - Hulke, Malcolm, 1972-1975, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Humor News magazine, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
  - Humor schools, 1979-1981 (Box 19)
  - Humor workshops, 1975-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Ideas, promotion, 1963, undated (Box 19)
  - International Brotherhood of Magicians, 1997-1999 (Box 19)
  - IBM United Kingdom Limited, 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - International Laughter Society, 1984 (Box 19)
  - International Platform Association, 1972-2001 (Box 19)
  - Jacobs, Seaman, 1970-1971, 1983-2006 (Box 19)
  - Jamison, Warren, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Jensen, Norman, 1973, 1984-1999, 2006 (Box 19)
  - John Rain Associates, 1968-1973, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Jones, L. Bevel, III, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Judson Welliver Society, 1985-2011, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Kasman, Louis P., 1979 (Box 20)
  - Kim Dawson Agency, 1974-1980, 1989 (Box 20)
  - King, Llewellyn, 2000-2001 (Box 20)
  - Kiplinger, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Kirk, John, 1976-1979 (Box 20)
  - Klein, Allen, 1988-1992 (Box 20)
  - Koering, Marilyn J., 1988 (Box 20)
  - Kreiling, Ernie, 1968-1970, 1988, 2004-2008 (Box 20)
  - Kupcinet, Irv., 1974, 1983, 1991-2002 (Box 20)
  - Kupferman, Stanley (Box 20)
    - 1964 -1965, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1966-1968, (4 folders) (Box 21)
  - Kurtz, Frank, 1984 (Box 21)
  - LaGuire, Al, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
  - Landmark Forum, 2001 (Box 21)
  - Lang, Margo Terzian, 1973-1977 (Box 21)
  - Larry King Show, radio program, 1979-1983 (Box 21)
  - Larsen, Erika, Genii magazine, 1994-1998 (Box 21)
  - Larson, Joe, 1979-1984, 1998- 2005 (Box 21)
  - Laugh-Makers magazine, 1982-1983, 1994 (Box 21)
  - Laughter Works, 1990-1991 (Box 21)
  - Leaders magazine, 1988 (Box 21)
  - Levey, Bob, 1994-1996 (Box 21)
  - Lewis, George Q., 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - Lewis, Shari, 1968-1983, 1990-1999 (Box 21)
  - Libby, Bill (Box 21)
    - "The Champs Speak," book project, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Life in the Pit, 1969-1972 (Box 21)
  - Lindner, Charles, 1980-1981, 1992-2001, (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Lindner, Charles, 2002-2013, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Linking Ring magazine, 1995-2005 (Box 22)
  - Long, Carolyn K., 2002 (Box 22)
  - Lowell, Juliet, 1979-1980 (Box 22)
  - Lufkin, Dan, 1974-1976 (Box 22)
  - Lund, Robert, 1978, 1991-1996 (Box 22)
  - Mack, Ferris, 1989-1992 (Box 22)
  - Magic magazine, 2000-2004 (Box 22)
  - Maher Studios, 1995-2000 (Box 22)
  - Malone, Paul, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Maloney, Stephen R., 1992-1993 (Box 22)
  - Marcantonio, Veda Ward, 1976-1979 (Box 22)
  - Marriott Corp., 1971-1977 (Box 22)
  - Marshall, Jay, and Frances Marshall, 1982-1986, 1995-2005 (Box 22)
  - Martin, Steve, 2000, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Marvin Josephson Associates, 1964-1978, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Marvin Josephson Associates, 1964-1978, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Massabny, Rich, 1993 (Box 23)
  - Matheson, Sally, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Mathias, Barbara, 1983 (Box 23)
  - McCaffrey, Joseph F., 1983-1996 (Box 23)
  - McGinnis, Mack, undated (Box 23)
  - McManus, Ed, 1990-1991 (Box 23)
  - Medhurst, Martin J., 1984 (Box 23)
  - Meetings & Conventions magazine, 1970-1985 (Box 23)
  - Merriam-Webster, Speaker's Handbook of Humor, 1999-2001, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Meyers, Hal, circa 2013 (Box 23)
  - Mihalec, John, 1978, 2007-2008 (Box 23)
  - Mitchell, Greg, 1981 (Box 23)
  - Mocerino, Gus, 1981 (Box 23)
  - Modern Maturity magazine, 1986-1987 (Box 23)
  - Monroe, Doug, 1990-1991, 2004 (Box 23)
  - Moran, Susan, 1982-1984, 1992-1995 (Box 24)
  - Morrison, Samuel D., Jr., 1986-1988 (Box 24)
  - Mott, Robert L., 1971, 1999-2000 (Box 24)
  - Murphey, Bob, 1992-1995 (Box 24)
  - National Association for Corporate Speaker Activities, 1983-1987 (Box 24)
  - National Association of Government Communicators, 1977 (Box 24)
  - National Association of Mature People, 1983 (Box 24)
  - National Comedy Hall of Fame, proposed, 1993-1998 (Box 24)
  - National Enquirer, 1974-1977 (Box 24)
  - National Press Club, 1977, 2001, 2008 (Box 24)
  - National Speakers Association, 1977-1984 (Box 24)
  - Nation's Business magazine, 1990 (Box 24)
  - Nebel, Long John, 1970, 1978 (Box 24)
  - New books, 1972-1977 (Box 24)
  - New Satirist magazine, 1981 (Box 24)
  - Newsbeat newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box 24)
  - Newsday Specials Syndicate, 1967-1970, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - New York Times, 2004 (Box 24)
  - Nilsen, Don L. F., 1980-1987, 2000-2008 (Box 25)
  - Norman, Shirley, 2000-2004 (Box 25)
  - O'Connell, Walter E., 1978 (Box 25)
  - Orben Productions, circa 1960-circa 1967 (Box 25)
  - Orleans, Anne, undated (Box 25)
  - Outlet Book Co., 1978 (Box 25)
  - Parvin, Landon, 1980, 1987, 1993 (Box 25)
  - Pattis, S. William, 1978, 1984-1999 (Box 25)
  - Peet, Richard George Clayton, 1994-2000 (Box 25)
  - Pendleton, Winston K., 1980-1984 (Box 25)
  - Perret, Gene, 1981-1984, 1992-2001 (Box 25)
  - Peter, Lawrence J., 1979-1980 (Box 25)
  - Phillips, Arthur, 1972, 1986-1990 (Box 25)
  - Playboy magazine, 1966-1976 (Box 25)
  - Portnor, Ralph, 1967, 1984, 2000-2008 (Box 25)
  - Potomac Speakers, 1980-1989 (Box 25)
  - Powers, Helen, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Prentice Hall, 1990 (Box 25)
  - Presidential Speechwriters Roundtable, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Preston, Charles, 1984-1999, 2006 (Box 26)
  - Pritzker, Robert A., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Program Associates, 1973-1994 (Box 26)
  - Psychology Today magazine, 1978-1979 (Box 26)
  - Pullen, Kaye, 1996-2002 (Box 26)
  - Pulse of Broadcasting magazine, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Quote magazine, 1973-1991 (Box 26)
  - Ragaway, Martin A., 1971-1976 (Box 26)
  - Random House, 2010-2012 (Box 26)
  - Raniello, John, 1977-1983 (Box 26)
  - Rauscher, William V., 2000-2007 (Box 26)
  - Reader's Digest magazine, 1969-1971, 1981-1998, 2008-2009 (Box 26)
  - Real People, television program, 1979 (Box 26)
  - Red Skelton Hour, television program, 1965-1977, (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - Red Skelton Hour, television program, 1980-1984, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Regency Books, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Rhine, Larry, 1970-1976, 1992 (Box 27)
  - Riordan, Gene, 1992-1994 (Box 27)
  - Rogers, Robert B., 1976, 1994-1996, 2003 (Box 27)
  - Ross, Stanley Ralph, 1992-1993 (Box 27)
  - Rushford, Greg, 1982-1983 (Box 27)
  - Russell, Pat, 2001 (Box 27)
  - Safire, William, 1985-1994, 2005 (Box 27)
  - St. Martin's Press, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Sandall, Simon, 2004 (Box 27)
  - Sands, June, 1992-1993 (Box 27)
  - Sansom, Art, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Schell, Ronnie, 1987-1994, 2000-2009 (Box 27)
  - Schiller, Bob, 1972-1977, 1992, 2012 (Box 27)